<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on BlairCostelloe.com</title>
    <link>https://blaircostelloe.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on BlairCostelloe.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 10:33:41 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blaircostelloe.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://blaircostelloe.com/sections/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 18:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blaircostelloe.com/sections/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a biologist with a background in immunology, molecular toxicology and behaviour. Originally from the Black Forest region of Southwestern Germany, I began my studies at the University of Freiburg under Prof. Dr. Klaus Warnatz at the Centrum für Chronische Immundefizienz (CCI), conducted my Erasmus at the University of Uppsala, and recently completed my Masters of Biological Sciences at the University of Konstanz, in the Department of Collective Behaviour at the Max-Planck-Institute for Animal Behaviour under Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interests</title>
      <link>https://blaircostelloe.com/sections/interests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 12:03:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blaircostelloe.com/sections/interests/</guid>
      <description>My first experience in research, working in a molecular immunology lab isolating B cells and evaluating their cytokine expression, fostered in me a deep interest in molecular biology. During my Erasmus I became interested in the ecological aspect of biology and took courses in limnology and marine biology. Not neglecting the molecular opportunities there, I also attended courses in human physiology and evolutionary genetics.
During my Master’s studies, I became interested in linking the broader ecological and behavioural impacts to underlying molecular mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>https://blaircostelloe.com/sections/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 10:53:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blaircostelloe.com/sections/skills/</guid>
      <description>Cell culture, microscopy, immunostaining, FACS, B cell isolation, cell viability assays, PCR/qPCR, ELISA, SDS Page, Western Blot, Primer design, DNA/RNA isolation and microsatellite analysis, genetic and behavioural data collection in the field
Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Photoshop; Basics in GraphPad Prism, Matlab, Processing, Python, OpenCV, Java, and R
Project planning and management, data collection, experimental design</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://blaircostelloe.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 09:28:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blaircostelloe.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a wildlife biologist interested in the natural history, behavioral ecology, and conservation of free-ranging animals. I earned my Ph.D. from Princeton University’s Department of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology in 2014. There I studied the maternal and antipredator behavior of Thomson’s gazelle, a small East African antelope. For that project I spent many months working at the beautiful Ol Pejeta Conservancy in Laikipia, Kenya. I adore field biology and enjoy the challenges of designing and executing projects in unpredictable environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://blaircostelloe.com/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 09:28:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blaircostelloe.com/research/</guid>
      <description>Below are links to descriptions of past and current research projects.
Feel free to check out my CV and publications. You can also find me on ResearchGate and Google Scholar.
Research projects: Herd Hover: Collective detection in savannah ungulates
Thomson&amp;rsquo;s Gazelles</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://blaircostelloe.com/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 09:28:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blaircostelloe.com/resources/</guid>
      <description>Herd Hover project website – Drones! Collective behavior! Max Planck Institute of Animal Behavior Centre for the Advanced Study of Collective Behaviour Department of Collective Behavior University of Konstanz Ol Pejeta Conservancy* Mpala Research Center Support
European Commission Marie Sklodowska-Curie Actions NVIDIA Animal Behavior Society Former Affiliations
Princeton University Department of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology Rubenstein Lab Saint Louis Zoo San Diego Zoo Institute for Conservation Research Washington University in St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://blaircostelloe.com/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 09:45:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blaircostelloe.com/publications/</guid>
      <description>Tuia, D.*, Kellenberger, B.*, Beery, S.*, Costelloe, B.R.*, Zuffi, S., Risse, B., Mathis, A., Mathis, M., Van Langevelde F., Burghardt, T., Kays, R., Klinck, H., Wikelski, M., Couzin, I.D., van Horn, G., Crofoot, M., Stewart, C. and Berger-Wolf, T. Seeing biodiversity: perspectives in machine learning for wildlife conservation. Accepted at Nature Communications. Preprint available.
Graving, J.M., Chae, D., Naik, H., Li, L., Koger, B., Costelloe, B.R. and Couzin, I.D. 2019. DeepPoseKit, a software toolkit for fast and robust animal pose estimation using deep learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://blaircostelloe.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 17:45:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blaircostelloe.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>email: blair.costelloe@ab.mpg.de</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomson&#39;s Gazelles</title>
      <link>https://blaircostelloe.com/thomsons-gazelles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 10:06:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blaircostelloe.com/thomsons-gazelles/</guid>
      <description>Maternal and antipredator behavior of Thomson’s gazelles Parents with dependent offspring face interesting challenges in optimizing their behavior to maximize their reproductive success. They must meet all the same requirements as non-parents – getting enough to eat, avoiding predation – while also protecting and providing for one or more vulnerable, needy offspring. Thomson’s gazelles are a great system in which to study maternal decision-making, behavior, and trade-offs for several reasons: Cheetahs feeding on an adult male Thomson&amp;rsquo;s gazelle Cheetahs feeding on an adult male Thomson’s gazelle</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
